Interviewer: What do you think are the benefits of living in a multicultural society?
Ida: I think the benefits of living in a multicultural society are all positive.
I don’t think there’s a negative you can take from it.
You experience different aspects of different cultures, food, music, perspectives,
and I think, most importantly, it allows you to gain a perspective on your own existence,
almost sort of, that the only way of life is not yours, there are different ways of looking at it.
And for me, personally, I, I grew up, sort of, all over the world,
we moved to a different country every three years of my life.
And, when there, we were always part of a very international community,
but also experiencing different countries in a very multicultural way and, a,
a kind of, seeing multiculturalism in different countries and how it works in different countries…
Tim: Which countries were they?
Ida: Um, to – from Uruguay to Italy to Austria to Belgium…places like that.
And so, I think it just, it allows you to be part of a different community
and allows you to be more open-minded and more understanding and…
Tim: Yeah. That’s so true, yeah.
Ben: Yeah, yeah, no, I agree.
I mean, for me, I’ve got, I’ve got a young son who’s about to start school,
er, later this year and so we’ve had to try and choose a school for him.
And one of the things that was important to me was to choose a school
that did have a lot of different cultures, a lot of different languages and,
um, I didn’t realize that it was important until we actually started looking at different schools.
Tim: Yeah, yeah.
Ben: And then there was one school in particular that really stood out
and one of the reasons was because, not only do they have lots of different languages,
cultures, backgrounds, but they really, they really celebrate that,
and so they really encourage the kids and the parents to contribute to the school and to,
to bring part of themselves and their culture and their identity to the school and really celebrate that.
I, I thought that was wonderful.
Ida: That reminds me of an experience I had in school in first grade when I was living in Uruguay,
we had this presentation and we all had to sing a song that they’d written,
and we all had to wear our national dress.
And the song was like ‘Ida is from Sweden, Fabiola’s from Brazil…’
and so everybody – it was a class of 20 kids and we were all from different places
and it’s just really important, and I think it just
– I then become very aware, when I am in a place that is…
not that, and it makes me slightly uncomfortable, sort of, I don’t know…
Tim: I think it’s really important, um, especially in the times we live in now, um,
and I, I think it’s, sort of, almost a, a, a natural human tendency to be slightly suspicious
or afraid of, you know, anything that looks different or, sort of, ‘the other’.
And I think multicultural societies encourage you to understand that,
um, different people act, talk, dress, er, behave in different ways, and that, um,
and that, you know, variety is good.
Ida: Especially at the moment, I think,
when we’re living in a time when ‘othering’ is coming back in a big way.
Tim: Yes, and suspicion is kind of like, you know, part of, part of the landscape again.
I think it’s really important to understand other people
and other cultures and to be empathetic towards that.
Ida: Absolutely.
Ben: Yeah, yeah.